# **Luke James Stringer**

<u>luke@stringer.dev</u> · 07454 112212 30 Rivelin Park Crescent, Sheffield , S65GF

## **PROFILE**

An adept engineering manager with 9 years commercial iOS development experience. A confident, organised, pragmatic and honest leader, I have a proven record of delivering multi-platform projects to private and public sector organisations. I enjoy collaborating with colleagues across disciplines, and I am passionate designing, architecting, coding, testing and deploying mobile and web applications.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Objective-C, Ruby, Unix
- Core Data, Networking, NSOperation, Core Location, UIDocument, StoreKit
- iOS Signing and Provisioning
- Object & Protocol Oriented Development, Test Driven Development
- Swift Package Manager, CocoaPods, Git Submodules
- Xcode, Fork, SourceTree, Postman, Charles, Visual Studio Code, Pixelmator
- App Store Connect, TestFlight, Apple Developer Portal, Apple Business Manager
- GitLab, GitHub, GitHub Pages, Heroku, Azure Functions, Jekyll
- Visual Studio App Center, Bugfender, RevenueCat

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

# Head of Development, 3Squared Ltd — 2018–Present

- Lead a team of 25 developers (Native iOS, Native Android, ASP.NET, Vue.js) to build the RailSmart software suite. Implemented a cohesive and inclusive team vision and management approach.
- Recruited at multiple levels (Graduates to Senior Engineers), growing the team by 50% during the first year of my leadership. Implemented a graduate scheme to train and mentor junior developers.
- Designed and embedded a technical strategy to move to SaaS, focusing on simpler, consistent tech stacks and approaches, across different platforms and 20+ codebases. Standardised reusable packages with SPM, NPM, NuGet, using them across the product suite in both new and old projects.
- Planned and managed technology transitions including CocoaPods to Swift Package Manager, ASP.NET Web Forms to Vue.js, Octopus Deploy to Azure DevOps, and on-prem GitLab to GitHub.
- Mentored developers new to leadership, allowing me to manage the larger team through them.
- Managed team resourcing, identifying developers with the right technical and soft skills for projects.
- Defined the web API architecture to integrate with systems at Network Rail. Worked with internal and external technical teams to implement a phased approach to integration with our applications, with longer terms goals to offer the solution as a product to the wider market.
- Planned the transition to Federated Identity for our SaaS products. Identified the complexities across our platforms, aligning them with infrastructure, testing, UX, and cost considerations.
- Regularly a part of sales activity, working on bid and tender documentation to win big contracts with Network Rail and HS2. Defined technical approach to delivering software in multi-year iterations.
- Managed a quick transition into remote work in March 2020. Adapted my communication approach and the team structure to better suit remote work, supporting individual team member personally.

## Head of Mobile, 3Squared Ltd -2015-2018

• Lead a team of 6 iOS and Android developers, supporting and guiding both their technical and professional development through 1-2-1s, goal setting and appraisals.

- Planned and managed the transition from Objective-C to Swift (starting at version 2.2). Defined our best practise for migration and interoperability. All new projects used 100% Swift after 2017, and older, larger Objective-C codebases were gradually re-written; now 75% in Swift by 2021.
- Standardised iOS components into small, reusable packages using CocoaPods. Used them across all new and old projects, and open sourced as <u>The Peak Framework</u> on GitHub.
- Technical leadership and iOS development on projects with tight timelines and a challenging clients. I organised the team to work concurrently. I gave updates to clients and worked with Project Management to update company directors on our progress.
- Worked with Operational Management Team to implement new policies such as Agile rituals, standardised appraisal approaches, and inclusive recruitment principles.
- Responsible for managing the company's App Store Connect and Enterprise Developer Accounts, as well as supporting the setup and admin of customers' Apple accounts and MDMs.
- Reduced errors and saved time by automating builds. Used Ruby and xcodebuild to standardise app versioning and signing. Released for QA and production (App Store) using Team City on a Git push.

## Senior iOS Developer, 3Squared Ltd -2014-2015

- Mentored mobile developers, designed induction projects and trained them in our best practices.
- Trained the team in XCTest and TDD, and best practise for Git and branching with GitFlow.
- Built multiple native iOS app in the RailSmart Suite. Specialised in data synchronisation performance, identifying best approaches for Core Data, threading, web API calls and JSON serialisation.
- Completed a research project for Crossrail. Used iBeacons, Core Location, and trilateration to determine user position. Ran trials at the Bond Street site and wrote a recommendations report.

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

## **Pivot for iOS** – Launched May 2021 – getpivot.app

- Build, configure and visualise pivot tables just like Microsoft Excel.
- Used TDD to build a Swift algorithm to parse a CSV file into a pivot table. Open sourced as <a href="PeakPivot">PeakPivot</a>. Integrated into the app using the Swift Package Manager.
- Used UIDocumentBrowser to load CSV files, and save custom ".pivot" files. Integrates with RevenueCat for receipt validation of in-app-purchases.

# **Public Speaking** — <u>stringer.dev/talks</u>

- Topics: Git Best Practise, Open sourcing Swift Packages, Transitioning to Swift, Swift Errors
- Spoke at: DDDNorth, UIKonf 2020 (remote breakout room), NSManchester, SwiftYork, SheffieldSwift, University of Sheffield, Sheffield Hallam University.
- Attended: Swift Summit, Úll, UlKonf, ADDC, iOSDevUK, iOSCon, DDD North

# **Transported for iPhone** – Launched 2014 – <a href="http://lukestringer90.github.io/transported\_website">http://lukestringer90.github.io/transported\_website</a>

- Live public transport departure times in South and West Yorkshire. Local database of transport nodes (NaPTAN) from gov.uk, seeded into Core Data
- Scraped departure board HTML data. Open sourced the parser as <u>LJSYourNextBus</u>.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Sheffield 2008-2012 - First Class Masters Degree (with honours) in Software Engineering

# **OTHER INTERESTS**

I enjoy playing acoustic and electric guitar, cooking, and spending time with my partner and 3 year old son. I blog at <a href="stringer.dev">stringer.dev</a>, and I'm active on Twitter and GitHub as @lukestringer90